A Guide to the Charles E. Culpeper Foundation, Inc. records FA025
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Accession 2, 1875, 1878, 1916-2001 1969-2001; 2; 28 Cubic Feet
  - Historical Files, 1875-1995 1927-1952; 4
    - Daphne Seybolt Culpeper Sperl, 1927, 1937-1952; 4
      - Expenses and Savings Accounts, 1927, 1938-1942, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 46)
        Expense Record, 1927; Sale of Packard to Coca-Cola Bottling Company, 1939; Passbooks: Seamen's Bank for Savings, The National City Bank of New York, Bowery Savings Bank, National City Bank of New York, Dry Dock Savings Institution, Greenwich Savings Bank
      - Memberships, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Printed Matter, 1938, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 48)
        Time Table, Italian-Central American-South Pacific, 1938; Color Brochure, 'Napoli Canta'; Transport tag with string tie, multiple languages; 'Le Coultre Watches and Clocks' Booklet; 'Where Sick Folks Get Well,' Baker Hospital, Iowa, 1938; Newspaper article pertaining to role of award of monies to widow of hit and run victim,undated; Inheritance notice in newspaper from mother's estate.
      - Wolfpit Hill Road - Sperl Dreamy Hollow, Norwalk, Connecticut, 1940-1952 (Box 4, Folder 49)
        Home improvement construction, carpentry, tax, water bills.
    - Daphne Seybolt Culpeper Sperl Family, 1875-1955; 5
      Documents about the Seybolt and the Sperl families are included.
      - George W. Sperl Family, 1930-1933, 1941-1946 (Box 4, Folder 50)
        Consolidated Edison Company of New York, 1944-1946; Gresham Realty Company, Inc., Letters, Invoices, Correspondence, 1930-1933, 1944; New York Telephone Company, February-August 1945
      - Estate of Elbertha Seybolt Claussen, 1875, 1878, 1931, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 51)
        'In Loving Remembrance...'; James Mornington, Last Will and Testament, 1878; Burial plot in Wayne County, Pennsylvania, August 10th, 1875.
      - George L. Clauson - Last Will and Testament, 1931 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      - George W. Sperl, 1938, 1942-1945, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 53)
        Warranty Deed, George W. Sperl, Executor, Estate of Sadie Bryan Sperl Grand Avenue and Greene Avenue, County of Kings; Norwalk General Hospital, Invoices, 1945-1946; Wedding invitation, Mrs. Bennie Teabeaut to Mr. Howell Ross Hanson, June 16, 1938.
  - Photographs, 1991-1992, 1996; 5
    Photographs taken on-site at academic, cultural, and environmental institutions which received grant awards from the Culpeper Foundation are included in this series, as well as portraits of Board members and Foundation employees. Photographs of the corporate office in Stamford, Connecticut, including interior furnishings and decorative arts, are also included. Color photographs of principals, Board members, and administrative staff are included.
    Series 5 photographs have been retained in original format, and for reference purposes have also been microfilmed in their original location within the files.
    - Board of Trustees, April 1992; 32 (4x6)" negatives, color (Box 6, Folder 1)
      Photographs were removed from Series 1.2.
    - Board of Trustees, December 1996; 3 (8 x 10)" 2 (5 x 7.5)" color (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Brandy Station Foundation, 1991; 4 (4 x 6)" color (Box 6, Folder 3)
      1. Francis J. McNamara, Jr., John Powell at Antietam, May 30, 1991 2. Bud Hall, Jamie Dial, May 30, 1991 3. Francis J. McNamara, Jr. and Don Pfanz, Fredericksburg Battlefield, May 31, 1991 4. Bob Davidson, Eric Campbell, Francis J. McNamara, Jr., Gettysburg, May 29, 1991
      Photographs were removed from Series 3.2.
    - Brandy Station Foundation, 1992-1996; 1 (8 1/2 x 11)" color (Box 6, Folder 4)
      September 1993
    - Portland School of Art, 1989-1990, 1993, 1995, 1997, 2000; 1 (8 x 5 3/4)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 5)
      'Student Brooke Zeiss reading a book'
    - Brooklyn Botanic Garden, 1984-1990, 1995; 2 (5 x 7)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 6)
      'New conservatory complex nearly completed,' June 10, 1987
    - Ravinia Festival, 1990-1993; 2 (8 x 10)" color (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Group portrait, indoors and outdoors, 1991
    - WNET Thirteen, 1977-1986, 1998; 2 (6 x 4)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 8)
      'Joe Albert's Fox Hunt,' and Other Stories from the Pine Barrens of New Jersey, January 1980
    - Winterthur Museum and Gardens, 1991-1996; 5 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Museum exhibit displays, American furniture, silver and porcelain, Colonial Period.
    - Foreign Policy Association, 1981, 1984-1988; 3 (8 x 10)" (Box 6, Folder 10)
      Student Town Meeting, 1987
      Photographs were removed from Series 3.3.
    - Hampshire College, 1988-1990; 5 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 11)
      1. Adele Simmons Hall - 62 seat lecture hall with special provisions for film, video, and computer displays, 1990 2. Computer laboratory for School of Communications & Cognitive Science, 1990 3. Exterior view of Adele Simmons Hall showing how side entrance opens to covered walkway connecting several academic buildings, 1990 4. Skylight of lobby of Adele Simmons Hall; beyond lobby is office of Dean of School of Communications & Cognitive Science, and faculty offices, 1990 5. Seminar room in Adele Simmons Hall, 1990 6. Unidentified, 1990
      Photographs were removed from Series 3.41.
    - Notre Dame School, 1985, 1987, 1990; 4 (5 x 7)" (Box 6, Folder 12)
      1. Loyola/Notre Dame Library, 1990, color 2. Library interior, main level, 1990, b/w 3. Library, card catalog reference area, 1990, b/w 4. Library, current periodicals area, 1990, b/w
    - Seattle University, 1985-1987; 4 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 13)
      Computer Resource Center, 1987
    - College of the Holy Cross, 1990-1994; 3 (3 1/2 x 5)" color (Box 6, Folder 14)
      1. Stein Hall, 1994 2. Stein Hall, Room 323, Proposed 40 person mini-theater, 1994 3. Stein Hall, Room 324, with Room 324A in background, present audio-language lab, proposed workstation environment, 1994
      Photographs were removed from Series 3.42.
    - Lake Forest College, 1983-1990; 3 (5 x 7)" (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Language laboratory, individual carrels and group study carrels, 1990
    - Skidmore College, 1986-1988; 3 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 16)
      Students and equipment in language laboratory, 1988
    - University of Scranton, 1988-1991; 1 (5 x 7)" color (Box 6, Folder 17)
      Postcard, Ecuador, 1989
    - Children's Television Workshop Library Consortium, 1986-1993; 2 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 18)
      1. Professor and student in library at computer 2. Dedication plaque from Culpeper Foundation
      Photographs were removed from Series 3.43.
    - University of Connecticut, 1983-1989; 3 (8 x 10)" color (Box 6, Folder 19)
      'Culpeper Video Library, 1989' 1. Jessica Bowen, Service Supervisor, compiling a database of library's video holdings 2. Viewing stations 3. Compact stack installation, capacity 4,500 cassettes
    - Bermuda Biological Station for Research, Inc., 1984-1994; 1 (8 1/2 x 11)" color (Box 6, Folder 20)
      'Weatherbird I, research vessel, May 1992'
      Photographs were removed from Series 3.5.
    - Human Resources Center, 1971-1972, 1974, 1978, 1986-1990; 3 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 21)
      1. Children viewing television, 1990 2. Children using computer equipment, 1990 3. Plaque, Charles E. Culpeper Foundation, Inc., 1990
    - The Melmark Home, Inc., 1974-1979, 1981-1983, 1985-1991, 1997; 1 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 22)
      'Aerial view of undeveloped land adjacent to home' October 31, 1975. Photo Credit: Bill Harris
    - National Audubon Society, 1975-1986; 2 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 23)
      'Prairie Cottonwood, Alkali Lake,' 1980
    - National Audubon Society, 1975-1986; 9 (5 x 7)" (Box 6, Folder 24)
      'Ordway-Whittell Kissimmee Prairie Sanctuary, Florida, 1984'
    - National Audubon Society, 1987-1988; 5 (8 x 10)" (Box 6, Folder 25)
      'Big Bend Stretch, Platte River, Nebraska,' 1987; Photo Credit: VIREO
    - North Carolina Outward Bound School, 1981-1982, 1985-1988; 2 (5 x 7)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 26)
      'Appendix E, Rustic building exterior and interior, 1981'
    - The Statue of Liberty-Ellis Island Foundation, undated; 1 (3 x 5)" color (Box 6, Folder 27)
      'Donors Wall, 1992'
    - Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, undated; Prints 1-4 and 7-10 are 5" x 7" in size. Print 6 is 9" x 6 1/2" in size. (Box 6, Folder 28)
      1-2. Greenhouse, 2,200 square feet, tall enough to grow a winter crop of corn 3-4. Construction of plant biochemistry addition to Delbruck Laboratory 5. Delbruck addition, upper and lower level floor plans. Line drawing. 6. Scale model of Delbruck Laboratory and plant biochemical addition 7-8. Cultivating and cross-pollinating corn at Uplands Farm, agricultural experiment station 9-10. Cytogenetics laboratory (exterior) and seed examination area
      Photographs were removed from Series 3.73.
    - Salk Institute, 1988-1994; 2 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 29)
      'Peptide Purification Center, 1994'
    - University of Wisconsin Medical School, 1983-1987; 7 prints, 8" x 10" in size. 12 images total. (Box 6, Folder 30)
      'The Behavioral Conceptualization and Treatment of Parkinsons Symptoms, 1983'
    - Frank J. McNamara, Jr. Retirement Party, September 13, 1999; 44 (8 x 10)"; 40 b/w 4 color contact sheets (Box 6, Folder 31)
      Photographs were removed from Series 5.
    - Charles E. Culpeper Foundation, Inc. - Office, undated; 70 (4 x 6)" prints 4 (5 x 7)" prints 1 (11 x 4)" print (Box 6, Folder 32)
      Stamford, Connecticut; 'Interior Furnishing and Staff Portraits'
    - Opera/Music Theatre Institute of New Jersey, undated; 1 (8 x 10)" b/w (Box 6, Folder 33)
      "Fellows of the Opera/Music Theatre Institute."
      Photograph was removed from an unknown series.
      Missing as of December 5, 2008.
- Charles E. Culpeper Foundation photographs, 1065
  Photographs
  - Culpeper Family (Box 56, Folder 685)
  - Culpeper Family: Cemetary (Box 56, Folder 686)
  - Culpeper Foundation: Medical Research (Box 56, Folder 687)
  - Miscellaneous: Georgia (Box 56, Folder 688)
  - New Hope Church, Georgia (Box 56, Folder 689)